KEVIN LAIRD JUX DESIGNER

PROFILE

I am a 2019 Interactive Media Design cum laude graduate from the University of Washington. As a passionate designer, I have experience developing several user interfaces utilizing design tools such as Sketch Illustrator, Photoshop, and Figma. Examples include a variety of different applications such as my website and a school project of a unique display of brain activity to enlighten self awareness.

I enjoy and value working with a team to achieve successful outcomes in delivering innovative results. Beyond academic rigor, my curiosity and self-motivation to expand my knowledge and expertise led me to learn frontend web development in order to empower myself to contribute to my future success.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

HTML
CSS
JavaScript
jQuery
SCSS
SASS
NodeJS
EJS
react.js

SOFTWARE

Sourcetree Adobe Suite InVision Figma balsamiq Sketch Zeplin

DESIGN

Web Design

UI Design
Personas
Use Case Scenarios
Lean UX
Agile Development
Wireframing
Site Mapping
Responsive Design

OTHER

AR/VR
Social Media
Marketing
Team-focused
Test-Cases

EDUCATION

BA INTERACTIVE MEDIA DESIGN (IMD)

University of Washington | Sep '17 - Jun '19

Mission: With its interdisciplinary approach to interaction design and emphasis on studio practice, IMD enables students to develop creative solutions to complex problems.



3.74 GPA

Societies/Clubs

UX Club
Phi Theta Kappa, National
Honors Society
Society for Collegiate Leadership
& Achievement (SCLA)

Awards

Cum Laude Honors

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Self-employed | 2019 - 2020 • 1 year

- Developed functional web applications that are user friendly and followed W3C standards to create an engaging and accessible user experience.
- Tested web applications for bugs and found fixes to create high quality websites.
- Designed web applications in Sketch and exported designs to Zeplin to accelerate production in launching products.

GAME DESIGNER

Digital Future Lab | Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 • 6 months - Internship

- Designed and tested engaging levels in the new puzzle game, "SEED" to create thought-provoking and memorable experiences for the users.
- Tested the multiplayer update for Ghostlight Manor to ensure a smooth and bug-free release.
- Utilized gitlab and Sourcetree to log bugs, update the supervising manager of completed tasks, and create a communicative environment between teams.

UI/UX DESIGNER

IntroSpect | Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 · 6 months - Academic

- Created deep self-reflection by converting brain-wave data into an augmented reality (AR) experience.
- Documented, recorded, and displayed the six-month design journey in a display exhibit, providing insight to hundreds of visitors.
- Researched scientific inner-workings behind the MUSE EEG brain sensor to create a more engaging and understandable experience.

QUALITATIVE RESEARCHER

Wing Luke Museum | Sep 2018 - Dec 2018 · 3 months - Academic

- Used data collected to create intuitive solutions to improving the visitor journey and increase guest return rate by 50%.
- Applied collected data to create verbal and visual surveys for guests and improved data collection quality in doing so.
- Final report's recommended solutions were used on-site and have been successful in their intended uses.

GAME DEVELOPER/ARTIST

Cataclysm Cleaner | Apr 2018 - Jun 2018 • 3 months - Academic

- Worked in the Unity Engine and coded in the C# language to develop designed game mechanics in a 3 month time-frame.
- Designed custom sprites and the user-interface to improve player experience and understanding of the game mechanics.
- Produced a video trailer to better showcase the game to others and increase visibility and understanding.